Finding Aid for the King Family Papers LSC.1025
UCLA Library Special Collections
King Family papers
1860-1920
UCLA Library Special Collections
King, Andrew Jackson
King Family
LSC.1025
1.0 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Andrew Jackson King (1836- ) was a lawyer (1858- ), district judge, a member of the California Legislature (1859-1860), and later, a Los Angeles county judge (1869). He also published the Los Angeles News, the first daily newspaper south of San Francisco (1865-1872). The collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, memorabilia, photographs, and printed material relating to the King family.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Remi Nadeau, 1965.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9919729913606533
Biography
Andrew Jackson King was born in 1836 in Georgia; he came to Los Angeles in July 1852; he was admitted to the bar in San Bernardino in 1858, and was district judge; moved to Los Angeles in 1859; was member of the California legislature, 1859-60; became Los Angeles county judge in 1869; published the Los Angeles News, the first daily newspaper south of San Francisco, 1865-72.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, memorabilia, photographs, and printed material relating to the King family of Los Angeles. Most of the correspondence is with Andrew Jackson King.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence (Box 1).
Miscellaneous and photographs (Box 2).
Judges -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Family papers.; King Family--Archives.; King, Andrew Jackson--Archives.
- Correspondence:, 1860-1920s
  - Correspondence to Andrew J. King from various persons., 1860s; 20 letters. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence to Andrew J. King from various persons., 1870s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence to Andrew J. King from various persons., 1880-1890s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from Andrew J. King to various persons, 1860-1874.; 5 letters. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mrs. Andrew J. King, 1898-1924. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Invitations, etc. A.J. King and Family, 1910-20. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miss Laura M. King (Daisy), 1887-1911. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous and Photographs
  - Miscellaneous Legal Papers. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Articles, Stories, etc. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Cards, Invitations, etc. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, Fragments, Receipts, etc. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, Articles, etc. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Keepsakes, Momentos, etc. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photographs. (Box 2, Folder 7)